ABEFE JOSHUA OLANREWAJU

Senior Front End Developer

E-Mail: Joshabefedev@gmail.com Address: 14 Victoria Street, Yaba, Lagos, Tel: 09081539986 | 08072099452

Objectives

Meticulous web developer with over 2 years of front end experience and passion for modern and responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. W3C web developer certification. Passionate about software architecture and cloud computing. Regular attendee of web developer meetups and hackathons.

Experience

Freelance Web Developer

2020 - present

- Built an ecommerce website to sell products online. Increased company sales by 58%.
- Designed a customer web form for a local ophthalmologist & optometrist specialist's office. Increased patient satisfaction scores by 30%.
- Developed a launch website for the Indie Documentary Freedom. Boosted streaming sales by 60%.
- Created a website and Facebook-linked donations website for a local charity. Raised donations by 38%. Over 160 communities reached with 200,000 beneficiaries.

Supply Chain Management Intern

Chevron Nigeria Limited, Lekki, Lagos.

2020-2021

- Focused on projects to improve the operations of the strategic procurement & contract department and other closely connected departments.
- Conducted professional market research, communicated with clients, and resolved any client problematic issues.
- Performed multiple daily procurement functions, completed weekly reports, and executed other tasks as required by managers.

Education

* Upper Credit - Computer Studies

Faedat College of Technology, Lagos.

Completion: 2013

Relevant Coursework: Computer Fundamentals, Typography, eColor Theory, Vectors, Illustration.

* A Grade - Web Design & Development Concentration

Inspire Vocational Academies, Lagos.

Completion: 2021

Relevant Coursework: Website Design, User Experience, Client-Side Development, Web Page Programming, Database Management Systems, Object-Oriented Programming, Web Architecture, Mobile Application Development.

* OND, Business Administration

The Polytechnic, Ibadan, Oyo. 2017- 2019

Skills

Hard Skills

- Creating web and mobile applications
- Maintaining, optimizing, troubleshooting, and improving websites
- Implementation of apps and landing pages from concept through deployment
- Work closely with other team members on the development team.
- Perform code reviews.
- Proficient understanding of
 - Programming Languages like HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, Python, Ruby and Ruby on Rails
 - o CSS Pre-processors Sass, LESS
 - o Version Control Git
 - o **CSS and JS Frameworks** AngularJS, Bootstrap
 - **Content Management Systems** (CMS) Wordpress

Search EngineOptimization (SEO)

• Performance Testing, Load Testing & Debugging

Soft Skills

- Leadership Skills
- Ability to work with minimum supervision
- Collaborating with product and development teams
- Crafting an excellent customer experience
- Ability to create new ideas
- Sociable and quick learning new skills
- Ability to impact knowledge to others
- Maintaining excellent relationships with clients
- Excellent Communication Skills
- Time Management Skills
- Strong attention to detail
- Solving problems
- Decision Making

Certifications

- Front End Web Developer Professional Certification by W3C
- The Web Developer Bootcamp (Udemy)
- Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4
- Pluralsight Front End Web Development Certification

Hobbies

- Listening to Music
- Exercising
- Playing Video Games